<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <description>graphscope blog</description>
    <link>https://graphscope.io/blog/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://graphscope.io/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 11:31:59 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 11:31:59 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.2.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Introducing GraphScope Playground</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/images/try-record.gif&quot; alt=&quot;try-record.gif&quot; /&gt; 
Today we released &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/alibaba/GraphScope/releases/tag/v0.2.0&quot;&gt;GraphScope 0.2.0&lt;/a&gt;.  With this release, we are happy to introduce &lt;a href=&quot;http://try.graphscope.app/&quot;&gt;GraphScope Playground&lt;/a&gt;, a hosted JupyterLab with GraphScope ready out-of-the-box. Now you can get started with GraphScope straight away in your browser without any hassle for setting it up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;signing-in&quot;&gt;Signing-in&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The GraphScope Playground is built on top of &lt;a href=&quot;https://jupyter.org/hub&quot;&gt;JupyterHub&lt;/a&gt;. At the moment, it only supports Github OAuth for signing-in. Please make sure you have a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/join&quot;&gt;Github account&lt;/a&gt; before proceed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/images/try-login.gif&quot; alt=&quot;try-login.gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open &lt;a href=&quot;https://try.graphscope.app/&quot;&gt;GraphScope PlayGround&lt;/a&gt; in your browser. You will be shown a landing page of GraphScope Playground. It only take a few clicks to get authenticated with your Github account. A JupyterLab session will be created for you in a few seconds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;in-the-playground&quot;&gt;In the Playground&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will be redirected to the JupyterLab interface after signing-in. It is a modern integrated development environment for Notebooks, where documents and activities integrate with each other, enabling new workflows for interactive computing in Python.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/images/raw-playground-snapshot.png&quot; alt=&quot;gs-snapshot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the left, there is a sidebar, where you can navigate your workspace with the file browser, as well as check the list of running kernels and terminals, the command palette, and the list of tabs in the main work area etc. One the right, it is the main work area, where tabs and panes can be created for the files and notebooks you edit. You can also open a terminal if you like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A JupyterLab session lives inside a docker container is specifically created for you after signing-in. The session will live for up to 120 mins (or 15 mins without user interactions). Based on the the official &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jupyterhub/singleuser:1.3&lt;/code&gt; image, we added necessary packages, tutorials and sample datasets for running GraphScope to the  Playground image. You are given 1 CPU core and 2GB memory for the JupyterLab container, and you are also given the access to a Kubernetes cluster with a limit of 16 CPU cores and 32GB memory for you to run GraphScope sessions. Following the convention of JupyterLab, the default working directory is &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/home/jovyan/&lt;/code&gt;,  where you can find tutorials at the root, datasets under the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;datasets&lt;/code&gt; folder and a &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;workspace&lt;/code&gt; folder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can open an existing / create a new notebook, and start coding with GraphScope straight away. If you want to access the files you edited at a later time, you can place them under &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;workspace&lt;/code&gt; folder. All the changes elsewhere will be reset after session ends. We place  &lt;strong&gt;a copy of the sample datasets&lt;/strong&gt; on K8s hosts, which can be &lt;a href=&quot;https://nbviewer.jupyter.org/github/alibaba/GraphScope/blob/main/tutorials/1_how_to_launch_a_session.ipynb#Mounting-Volumes&quot;&gt;mounted to the GraphScope pods&lt;/a&gt;. Please note that your local edits to the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;~/datasets&lt;/code&gt; won’t affect the copy on K8s hosts (&lt;em&gt;stay tuned!&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;tutorials&quot;&gt;Tutorials&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the GraphScope Playground, you have access to a set of comprehensive tutorials to get started with GraphScope. In the tutorials you could learn how to launch a session, to load graphs, and to run analytical analysis, interactive queries as well as graph neural network trainings in GraphScope. At the moment, we have the following tutorials included.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://nbviewer.jupyter.org/github/alibaba/GraphScope/blob/main/tutorials/1_how_to_launch_a_session.ipynb&quot;&gt;How to Create a Session&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://nbviewer.jupyter.org/github/alibaba/GraphScope/blob/main/tutorials/2_loading_graphs.ipynb&quot;&gt;Loading Graphs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://nbviewer.jupyter.org/github/alibaba/GraphScope/blob/main/tutorials/3_builtin_analytical_algorithms.ipynb&quot;&gt;Built-in Analytical Algorithms&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://nbviewer.jupyter.org/github/alibaba/GraphScope/blob/main/tutorials/4_writing_your_own_algorithms.ipynb&quot;&gt;Writing Your Own Algorithms&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://nbviewer.jupyter.org/github/alibaba/GraphScope/blob/main/tutorials/5_interactive_query_with_gremlin.ipynb&quot;&gt;Interactive Query with Gremlin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://nbviewer.jupyter.org/github/alibaba/GraphScope/blob/main/tutorials/6_unsupervised_learning_with_graphsage.ipynb&quot;&gt;Unsupervised Learning with GraphSage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://nbviewer.jupyter.org/github/alibaba/GraphScope/blob/main/tutorials/7_supervised_learning_with_gcn.ipynb&quot;&gt;Supervised Learning with GCN&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://nbviewer.jupyter.org/github/alibaba/GraphScope/blob/main/tutorials/8_node_classification_on_citation_network.ipynb&quot;&gt;A Complex Workflow: Node Classification on Citation Network&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;stay-tuned-for-new-features&quot;&gt;Stay tuned for new features&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With GraphScope Playground, we wish to make getting started with GraphScope as easy as possible. We are constantly working on improving the experience. If you have any questions or feedbacks, feel free to write a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/alibaba/GraphScope/discussions&quot;&gt;post at Github Discussions&lt;/a&gt;. Happy Coding!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please note that the service provided by GraphScope Playground is strictly limited to the trial of GraphScope only. Any other use is strictly prohibited. Your use of the service will be at your own risk. And we provide no warranties to the service.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 06:33:20 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://graphscope.io/blog/newsroom/2021/02/01/introducing-graphscope-playground.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://graphscope.io/blog/newsroom/2021/02/01/introducing-graphscope-playground.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Newsroom</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Release Notes: v0.2.0</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/images/release_note_t.png&quot; alt=&quot;release-note&quot; /&gt;
The GraphScope team is pleased to announce the 0.2.0 release after two-months development.
The 0.2.0 release is focused on better getting started experience for end-users and we have
make a lot of improvements since the last minor release. We have improved our documentation
a lot, and made the kubernetes integration work for more settings. We have also brought the
support for various I/O to make GraphScope suitable for more production environments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along with the 0.2.0 release we also bring &lt;a href=&quot;https://try.graphscope.app&quot;&gt;GraphScope Playground&lt;/a&gt; to users
for getting started with GraphScope easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We highlights the following improvements included in this releases:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Better Kubernetes integration.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;LoadBalancer&lt;/code&gt; service type has been supported in this release, which brings GraphScope to
vendored could environments like Alibabacloud, AWS and Azure.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;A &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;volumes&lt;/code&gt; parameter has been added to &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;graphscope.session()&lt;/code&gt; to allow users mount their
volumes (host path, or cloud volumes, etc.) to worker pods for input graph data and retrieve
results.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Enhancement for interactive query.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;GraphScope v0.2.0 added a &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;InteractiveQuery.traversal_source()&lt;/code&gt; method to allows an interative
query seamlessly works with the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;gremlinpython&lt;/code&gt; SDK.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Better I/O and serialization support.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;GraphScope v0.2.0 started to support various I/O, including Aliyun OSS, AWS S3, HDFS and other
storage services that the filesystem-spec could support, for input datasets and result sink.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;GraphScope v0.2.0 added a &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Graph.serialize()&lt;/code&gt; method to allow users serialize a graph to external
storage and restore it back via &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Graph.deserailize()&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Bugfix for learning engine.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;A bug in closing learning instance of a graph has been fixed along this release.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more detailed bugfixes and improvements that have been made in
this version, please refer to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/alibaba/GraphScope/releases/tag/v0.2.0&quot;&gt;complete changelog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 03:33:20 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://graphscope.io/blog/releasenotes/2021/02/01/release-notes-0.2.0.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://graphscope.io/blog/releasenotes/2021/02/01/release-notes-0.2.0.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>ReleaseNotes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Say Hello to GraphScope!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/images/releasing.png&quot; alt=&quot;graphscope-releasing&quot; /&gt;
The source code of GraphScope is released today!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;github repo: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/alibaba/graphscope&quot;&gt;https://github.com/alibaba/graphscope&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GraphScope aims to provide a single system that is able to support three
types of computation tasks, i.e., graph interactive query, graph analytics and graph deep learning.
We carefully design GraphScope with user-friendly interface and extensible programming APIs,
so that users can easily construct customized end-to-end graph processing pipelines involving
different types of graph computation tasks. In specific, GraphScope fully embraces the Python and
Gremlin ecosystem, and thus comes with a shallow learning curve for both data scientists and
developers. Under the hood, GraphScope comprises core engines specifically optimized for each
graph computation paradigm, and can smoothly orchestrate multiple engines to cooperate efficiently,
avoiding the complexity of manually stitching multiple independent systems together. GraphScope
can scale to ultra-large graphs, and run in industrial speed and robustness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GraphScope is released under Apache License 2.0. Any contributions are greatly appreciated!
You may reach us at &lt;a href=&quot;http://slack.graphscope.io/&quot;&gt;Slack channel&lt;/a&gt; or submit 
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/alibaba/GraphScope/issues&quot;&gt;GitHub issues&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 10:18:42 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://graphscope.io/blog/newsroom/2020/12/07/say-hello-to-graphscope.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://graphscope.io/blog/newsroom/2020/12/07/say-hello-to-graphscope.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Newsroom</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
